助かったぜ　吸盤。 ってか　お前　タコだろ？
Fearsome monsters... Exotic creatures...
タッ…！
Vast riches... Hidden treasures...
新しい宿主を見つけないと 次の弾が育てられない ここは　オロソ兄妹に任せよう
I'll tear your body apart.
ウ…　ウハハ　ホントですね。 お久しぶりね！ なんちって　エへへ…。
Last x Test Of x Resolve
１つ　聞いていい？ はいはい　何なりと。
During the exam's Third Phase, which requires applicants to
reach Trick Tower's base
逃げるなら　何で 水の中に逃げなかったの？ どう考えても お前のほうが水中は有利だろ？ まさか カナヅチってオチじゃねえよな？
within seventy-two hours, Gon and his friends have incurred
a penalty of fifty hours.
今　湖に入れば　負傷してる　お前も 食われちまうってわけだ。
Gerreta, applicant #384,
is the fourth to pass.
違う？ いや　いえ…　っていうかですね あの　何というか　あの　その…。
Total time, twelve hours
and twenty-seven minutes. Eh...
テレパシー
Not bad, I guess.
ん？　誰と喋ってんだよ。 うわ！　間違えた！
If you hesitate on the first step,
you'll hurt yourself. Got it.
そうか　お前ら 電波で通信できるんだったな。 ボスか　俺の頭上で ウロチョロしてる野郎だろ？
Hey, Kurapika. Once we've spent fifty hours here, we'll have fewer than ten hours, right?
いやいや　あのですね…。
Yes, that's correct.
テレパシー おい　イカルゴ！ 返答しろ　イカルゴ！
That's way more than enough time!
テレパシー はい！　まだ戦闘中です。
You're a fool. What's that?
テレパシー そうか　邪魔したな。 テレパシー 何か分かったら　すぐ知らせろ。
Phase Three lasts seventy-two hours.
さすがに洞窟で何十匹も トンボが飛び回っていたら
And each phase is designed to weed out half of the remaining candidates.
敵も不審に思うだろうからな サテライトンボを 送り込むわけにいかん
So, on average, it's meant to
take seventy-two hours.
じゃあさ　取り引きしようぜ。 えっ！
Just more proof that you're an idiot.
そいつの能力を教えれば お前の命は　保証する。
Well, our chances of reaching
the goal within ten hours
１０秒以内に答えろ。
will depend on the remaining trials.
あぁ…。
Yeah, that's true.
あと８秒。
But when we've got a guy
who's so down on his luck, he can't even win a simple game
of rock-paper-scissors... What was that?! You deliberately lost a bet,
just to satiate your libido.
うぅ…。
Then you chose rock-paper-scissors,
a contest you couldn't win. Shut up!
６秒。
You surrendered without even a fight!
あう…。
I... I give!
イカによ…　生まれたかったんだ。
But I only wasted a second of our time.
特によ ユウレイイカにリスペクトでよ。
You lost, squandering fifty of our remaining hours. Take some responsibility, huh?
タコもイカも 似たようなもんだって思うかい？
Besides, what kind of Hunter
大違いだぜ。
is so bad at gambling? Shut up!
タコは　不細工だ。
You don't even want to become a Hunter...
イカは　イカしてる。 俺には イカのフォルムが神なのさ。
You only care about ruining our chances. And now, you'll have
the guilt eating at you
あと２秒。
for the rest of this exam phase.
仲間は　売れねえ！
Hey! What are you doing?
ああ　目で分かったよ
Sorry about that. Don't skateboard inside this tiny room!
期待するぜ。
Aww...
うぁ！ うおっ？
Can't sleep?
魚がジャンプできねえとでも 思ったか？　あ？
I can go two or three days without sleep.
このまま鍾乳石ごと かみ砕いてやる！
Ten hours have passed, huh... There aren't any windows,
so it's hard to tell.
テレパシー イカルゴ　応答せよ。
But it's probably morning.
テレパシー
Most likely.
痛くて声も出ねえか？　あ？
Hey, pipe down.
あ　ホッとする。 あぁ？
Let me sleep some more...
やっぱ　敵は おめぇみたいなクソがいい。 あっ？ すげぇ　殺りやすいから。
That stinks!
故に　おとり！
Bastard, you'd better not
be pretending to sleep.
テレパシー やりました　オロソ様！ テレパシー 奴にバッジを着けました！
Damn, now I'm totally awake...
テレパシー 成し遂げたのは コバーンめでございます！
And we still have forty hours left?
デジタル音？　頭の中から？
Oh, I thought you just had
なっ…
to stick bait on a hook,
and you could fish. Yeah. You have to think like a fish.
何!?
Think like a fish?
魚？　陸だぞ　ここ！ どういうことだ？ 全く気配が感じられなかった
Yep! How would a fish feel if it saw
bait dangling in front of it? Give me that.
まただ　刺さる瞬間まで 全く姿が見えず
Wow!
オーラでも感知できなかった
Let me try.
何だよ？　これ
Like this?
うっ！　ゴホッ。
You missed.
ヤバい…　全く 攻撃の気配が感じられない
Just watch. H-Hey... What are you doing?
テレパシー フフフ…。
Hey...
テレパシー １０８ポイント。
Just as planned! Nice. Hey, you'll tear my pants.
テレパシー 何をされてるか 見当もつかないかな？
Stop it...
テレパシー ちなみに　今は 君の頭に直接　話しかけてるぜ。
See? I caught him. Yep. What's that supposed to mean?
まっ　命があれば そのうち分かるさ。
I'm a fish now?! You don't have to get so mad. It's not like I'm gonna grill and eat you.
やはり　「念」で　つくられた魚
Don't mess with me, fool! Man, I can't even take a nap.
でなきゃ　あり得ない！
What are you smiling about?
刺さる瞬間まで
Nothing, really.
見ることも感じることもできない 攻撃なんて
You must be up to something again.
ぐっ！　うっ！　うわっ！
Of course not. I just want to spend
うん　いい感じさぁ。
the rest of my time here peacefully. Liar! I don't trust you, got it?
テレパシー
The feeling's mutual.
答えは　１つ！
Yes, the goal!
てめぇの能力…
Pokkle, applicant #53.
ダーツか！
Goz, applicant #371.
うっ！ ピンポン！
Both arrived simultaneously.
正解だ。
Total time, thirty hours
and four minutes.
だが　分かったところで 打つてがないのが俺達の能力。 何しろ　俺の念魚「ダツ」は…。
Damn. Old timer... In a tie, the applicant with
the lower number wins.
テレパシー お前の体に 刺さる瞬間まで　全く実体がない。 テレパシー つまり　防御不能。
These guys must be very skilled.
テレパシー フフフ…　ちなみに 左肩は　５４ポイントだ。
I would love to fight them eventually.
６トリプル。 ４。 １３。
You lost, squandering fifty of our remaining hours.
ブラボー！ 素晴らしいわ　兄さん　絶好調ね。
Take some responsibility, huh?
俺達は無敵さぁ　なぜなら…。
Ow!
開き直られて 「早く殺せ」とかさぁ ニヒルなヒーロー気取りで
Sommy, applicant #118,
is the thirteenth to pass.
「こんな死に方も悪くないな」 とか言われたらさぁ
Total time, sixty-one hours
and fifty-four minutes.
かなりイラっと来て 投げるのに影響するからさぁ。
Man, still ten hours left?
いつ死ぬか　いつとどめが 来るのかって　ビビりながら…。
I finished too early.
死んでもらうさぁ。 フフフ…。
Okay... Ready to go!
まだ…　まだ　だ…
One more minute.
クソ　相当　ヤバい…　な…
This is one long minute.
予想以上に… 血　流し過ぎてる
Ah... Wait up, Gon!
死ぬかもしれないんじゃ 出し惜しみしても しょうがないな さてと いよいよ　ファイナルターンだ。
Hunter Vocabulary Bored
さぁ　最後の一投だ。
We should have taken those stairs down. Shut up!
信じてるわ　兄さん。
We all agreed on this route!
だろ？
We need to move on. So obviously,
we want to open the door.
イェイ！ イェイ！
I've had enough of your crap.
いや。 やっぱり　兄さんは世界一だわ！
Wait, I pressed O.
死にざまを見て来る。 俺も行くよ。
Don't lie... You specialize in ruining
other people's chances!
死体の肉を　コバーンへの 褒美にやらなきゃな。
Sorry, Leorio. Eh? I accidentally pressed the wrong button.
食べないの？
Huh? You owe me an apology.
おおっ！
I can't let that slide.
１つ　聞いていいか？ 何？ 何で急に 俺の疑いは晴れたんだ？
It's your own fault, for doing things to make me distrust you.
疑ってたっていうか
I don't owe you anything.
何で　ずっと 追いかけられてたのか
You make it sound like I'm to blame
分からなかったからさ。
for everything that's gone wrong.
だます気がないって 誓ってくれたしね。
What? Have you forgotten
はぁ？　それだけかよ！
who cost us those fifty hours?
それで　十分でしょ？ 十分じゃねえよ！
You're the one who made
a critical mistake.
「誓う」とか　「絶対」とか ウソつきの常套句じゃねえかよ！
Hey, Leorio...
一番　信じちゃいけねえ言葉だろ！
Shut up, Kurapika!
あっ…　俺は違ぇよ！
Stop this, guys.
ウソじゃねえよ！ １００％　トゥルーだぜ！
It's my fault for pressing
the wrong button.
じゃあ　いいじゃん。
Stupid. I'm moving on.
はぁ。
Wait, Killua!
俺もヤキが回ったかな
Hey, Gon...
いくら強くても　ガキはガキ
We're getting close to the goal.
こんな世間知らずと 一蓮托生　たくらむとはよ
What? Really?
それに　ウソだったら それはそれで気が楽だし。
Let's see... "This will be the last decision
made by majority rule.
気楽？
Are you ready?
容赦しなくていいから。
Choose O or X." That's it.
遠慮なく倒せる。
Am I ready?
くっ　このガキ…
You bet. Bastard...
何て…　何て目で見やがる
Stop! We don't have time to argue about this!
そうだ　だから　あの時…
Please select a path.
あの時も直感した
There are two choices.
こいつには　何かあると
One path allows five to pass, but is long and difficult.
こいつは　底が見えねえと
The other path allows only three, but is short and easy.
完璧に額のど真ん中 貫かれてるわ。
Incidentally, the long and difficult path
テレパシー フラッタ様 ターゲットを始末しました。
requires a minimum of forty-five hours.
テレパシー そうか　よくやった！
The short and easy path leads
テレパシー レオル様には　俺から　お前達の 昇進を強く推しておこう。
to the goal in approximately three minutes.
テレパシー ありがとうございます。 やったわ！ これで私達も師団長補佐よ！
Press O for the long and difficult path, and X for the short and easy path.
イェイ！ イェイ！ イェ…。 イェ…。 イッ？
If X is selected, two people must be secured to
the wall with handcuffs, before the door will open.
何で脳みそ貫かれて 生きてんだ？　てめぇ！
The examiners were very prepared.
なっ！ 吸盤だよ　タコの。
every weapon under the sun here.
ど…　そんな… どうやって　そんな小細工を？
Two out of five... So we're supposed to fight,
to decide the three who pass?
いや　っていうか 俺の…　俺のダツは絶対
Let me make this clear.
絶対に防御不可能のはずだ！
I'm going to press X.
ああ　防御なんか　してないぜ。
But I have no intention of staying behind.
刺さってから　つかんだんだよ。
I'll do whatever it takes to
be one of the three...
ダツが俺に刺さって 実体化した瞬間にな。
You're shameless.
お前のセリフから 俺の声は聞こえても
Had you not wasted fifty hours, we could have taken the long path.
姿までは見えてない場所に いるのは分かったから
Shouldn't you take responsibility
and stay behind?
つかんだ後に 魚のくちばしを折って
What?! I'm sure everyone else agrees!
吸盤をつける程度の 細工の時間は十分あった。
Have I said anything inaccurate? Hold on.
ダツをつかむなんて 超光速的な反射神経
We made it all the way here together.
人間に　あるわけねえだろ！
I want us all to pass together.
まぁ　もちろん　ダーツの矢が どこに来るか分からなきゃ いくら何でも無理さ。
Gon... Even if it's a big risk, I want to give it a shot! Come on...
けど　最後の一投だけは
You can't really call this a risk.
いつ　どこに投げるか 完全に分かる。
We have less than an hour.
ゲームを決める最後の一投は
Gon, there's only one choice
的の一番外枠に入れなければ ならない　ダブルアウトルール。
if you want to pass this exam.
そして　ゲームの種類は
There you have it.
ゼロワンの５０１。 うっ！
Now we have to decide how to
choose which three pass.
５０１ポイントから スタートして
Well, I'm planning on
ちょうど　０になるまで 投げるゲーム。
two of them being you and me.
プロの公式試合でも 使われているゲームだ。 お…　俺はゲーム名なんて 言ってねえぞ！
Heh, I've made it this far.
これがダーツを使った能力って 分かった瞬間に確信したさ。
I won't fail now. Whoever makes the first move wins.
４のダブルを思い出してな。
Must we really fight amongst ourselves?
ダブルインを使ったろ？
Tonpa, that was dirty!
よっぽど技術と自信がある証拠。 そんな奴が　公式のルールを 無視するわけがない。
In a fight, there's no such thing as dirty!
技術と自信がある奴は
Bastard!
公に認められたがるもんだからな。
Stop this, you two! Come on... Let's do it together.
あとは単純な計算と我慢。 刺さったポイントを ５０１から引いて行き
Before we start fighting, we have to choose O or X!
４０ポイント以下になるまで 耐える。
It's too late for that!
そして　その時が来たから
Time to put you in your place!
４０ポイント
Right back at you.
つまり額の所で　あらかじめ つかむ構えをとってた。
Seems our only choice is to fight.
それだけさ。 キルアは 反応をより速めるため
What should I do?
ダツが額に触れた時 皮膚の触覚から脳へ
Three minutes remain.
脳から手の神経へと 電気指令を伝えるのではなく
It's finally over...
オーラがダツを感知した瞬間 直接左手の神経に「つかめ」という 電気信号を送るように
Yeah, that took forever.
６歳で極めた カウントで１４４０ポイント。 修行の初歩だね。
Made it in time...
あんたが調子こいて…。
He's dead. The fool.
７歳だったかな？　まぁいいや 無駄口が過ぎたな。
Better to live and try again, than to pass and die.
急がなきゃ。
One minute remains.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
Looks like it'll just be
the nineteen here.
ハッ… うわ…
Kurapika, applicant #404,
is the twentieth to pass.
これ全部　俺の血かよ
Killua, applicant #99,
is the twenty-first to pass.
何か…　風呂　入ってるみてぇに 温けぇ…
Gon, applicant #405,
is the twenty-second to pass.
いや…　そんなこと考えてる 場合じゃねえよ
Total time, seventy-one hours
and fifty-nine minutes. My butt hurts...
行かなきゃ…
I didn't expect a slide
ヤベェ…
Thirty seconds remain.
今度は…　寒ぃ
That was really close. My hands are covered with blisters.
クソ せっかく　さっきの戦いで
Same here.
すげぇ技のヒント
Leorio, applicant #403,
is the twenty-third to pass.
つかんだのによ
Tonpa, applicant #16,
is the twenty-fourth to pass.
俺…　ここで　死ぬのか？
Total time, seventy-one hours
and fifty-nine minutes.
ゴン…　悪ぃ…
My hands are blistered, but all five of us cleared
the tower together.
役に…　立てな…　か…
All thanks to Gon!
タコ…？
We entered the long and difficult path.
タコって言うな!! ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…！
Then cut a hole in the wall, to sneak into the short and easy path.
何…　やってんの？
Man, I can't believe you actually came up with
that idea on the spot.
見たら分かんだろ 仲間　裏切ってんだよ！ カッコ悪ぃだろ っていうか　もう喋るな。
I realized that we could break
the walls, using the weapons. But it took over fifty minutes.
モグリだが医者は知ってるからよ 地下水流に乗れば　すぐだ！ それまで　踏ん張れ！
In an extreme situation, you were able to calmly evaluate our two options and circumvent them.
バカかよ　せっかく 助けて…　やったのに…　よ…。
That's what makes you special.
これで… おめぇまで…　お尋ねもんだ…。
The Third Phase of the exam is over.
分かってるよ　そんなこと！
Twenty-five applicants have passed.
自分でも　訳　分かんねえよ！
One has died.
けどよ　こんな俺のこと こんなタコな俺のこと カッコいいって 言ってくれた奴を
Though the team members
had their differences, Gon was able to bring them together,
to overcome the trial.
「友達になれる」って 言ってくれた奴を
However, a friend today may
become a foe tomorrow.
見殺しになんか　できるかよ!!
Gon doesn't know that before long, they'll be pitted
絶対に助けるからな！
against each other,
in brutal, individual battles.